Guide to the Ralph R. Sundquist Papers 1909-1980
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Ralph R. Sundquist Papers
1909-1980
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Cage 601
Sundquist, Ralph R., 1894-
8 Linear feet of shelf space 16 Boxes + 1 Oversize folder
The papers of Ralph Sundquist consist of correspondence, business documents, reports, enclosures, and brochures related to agriculture and his civic interests.
Ralph Roger Sundquist was born in Galesburg, Illinois, on 5 January 1894, to the Rev. and Mrs Hjalmar Sundquist. In 1910, the family moved to the Yakima Valley because Hjalmar had health problems he thought curable in a warm, dry climate. Ralph graduated from Yakima High School in 1912 and earned a Bachelor of Science degree in Horticulture from the State College of Washington in 1916. A year later, he received a Master of Science degree in Horticulture from the State College. He taught biological courses for a year at Whitworth College, in Spokane, before returning to Yakima, where he taught high school for two years. About this time he married Elaine Fager.
The Sundquist family entered the apple business soon after arriving in the Yakima Valley. Around 1920, Ralph purchased his first orchard near Gleed. The Sunnyslope orchards did very well through the rest of the decade, raising a number of apple varieties for nationwide markets. These included the Starking Red Delicious. The early 1930s economic downturn nearly left Sundquist in financial ruin. In 1948, Sundquist and a colleague opened the Hansen Fruit and Cold Storage Company, in Yakima. He later established the Sundquist Fruit and Cold Storage Co. In 1966, he built a new controlled-atmosphere storage facility for processing, storing and shipping apples from his 850 acres of orchards and those of others.
Sundquist was an active member of the community. He was an early communicant of Yakima's First Presbyterian Church, giving much of his time and money. He made large contributions for improvements in the congregation's pipe organ in the 1940s and 1950s, and for stained glass windows. He was president of the Lower Naches Telephone Company, the the Yakima District Horticultural Society, and the Washington State Horticultural Association. He also as a board member of the Yakima YMCA, founding director of the Yakima Valley Memorial Hospital (later a trustee), director of the Yakima Valley College, and member of the Yakima School board. Sundquist also helped organize Yakima's first television station, KIMA-TV, and Yakima's educational television station.
Early in the 1950s, Ralph became a member of the Atomic Energy Commission's Personnel Advisory Board for the Hanford Project. He helped evaluate potential employees' security clearance applications. At this time, he also became a director of the San Francisco Federal Reserve Bank's Seattle Branch. In 1963, Ralph and two dozen other regional agribusinessmen travelled around the world as part of the U.S. State Department's People-to-People cultural exchange program. They observed crop production methods in many developing Middle Eastern and Asian countries. Among his many honors for civic activities, Ralph Sundquist received the Boy Scouts of America's Silver Beaver Award for his commitment to the Fort Simcoe Council. He also won the Greater Yakima Valley Chamber of Commerce's Award of Merit for outstanding community service. He received the State College of Washington's Certificate of Merit.
Many terms historically used to describe individuals and communities with disabilities are offensive and were used to dismiss, discount and dehumanize these individuals and communities. Terms often focused on a perceived impairment and not the person. MASC recognizes the harm caused by these terms. We retain the language in this finding aid to document history and preserve context.
The papers of Ralph Sundquist consist of correspondence, business documents, reports, enclosures, and brochures related to agriculture and his civic interests. Correspondence and business documents make up the first series. The subject files that make up the second series cover a variety of subjects, chiefly related to apple growing and shipping. Agricultural reports by Sundquist, mostly related to apple growing, make up the third series. The fourth series, is focused on Sundquist's civic endeavors with public education, junior colleges, hospitals, churches and the Federal Reserve System. A number of historically significant sales brochures, chiefly for agricultural equipment, have been kept as a distinct fifth series. The final, sixth, series is made up of various oversize materials.
The papers are arranged in six series, mostly organized alphabetically within each. The present arrangement preserves much of the original organization. Unfiled materials have been added to the corresponding series in places where apparent. Other parts of the collection had no filing order when received and have been arranged in several sequences that combine like materials.
This collection is open and available for research use.
WSU acquired the Ralph R. Sundquist Papers in 1980 (MS80-46) from Ralph's son, Marvin V. Sundquist.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Sundquist, Ralph R., 1894- -- Archives
Stark Bro's Nurseries & Orchards Co. -- History; People-to-People (Organization) -- History; State College of Washington -- Alumni and alumnae; Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco. Seattle Branch
Yakima (Wash.) -- History
Apple growers; Apple industry -- Washington (State) -- History; Apples -- Washington (State) -- Marketing -- History; Apples -- Diseases and pests -- Washington (State) -- History; Apples -- Storage -- Washington (State) -- History; Land use, Rural -- Washington (State) -- History
Washington (State); Agriculture
- Series 1. Correspondence, Statements, etc.
  - Correspondence A, Misc. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Assets and Liabilities of Ralph Sundquist (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Associated Oil Company, San Francisco (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Atlantic Commission Company, Fruits and Produce, Seattle (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence B, Misc. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Noel Bakke, Wenatchee-Okanogan Cooperative Federation (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - K. K. Baxter and M. L. Lee, Mortgage No. 1050, Yakima (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Albin Berg, Land Sale, 1919-23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Harry G. Braham, First Presbyterian Church, Yakima (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - N. K. Buck, concerning Dr. Ferry (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence C, Misc. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sid B. Carnine, Inc., Carlot Broker and Distributor (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - R. Bert Carter (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chinook Hotel, Remodelling, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Wilson Compton, President, WSC (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Earle E. Corwin, Sunshine Ranch, Wapato (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence D, Misc. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Davis Manufacturing Company, Davis, California (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - De Laval Steam Turbine Co., Seattle office (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence E, Misc. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Earl Fruit Company of the Northwest, Spokane (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Egg-Safety Carton Corporation, Chicago (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Rev. Henry E. Ek, Swedish Evangelical Mission Church (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence F, Misc. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Elaine Fager (Elaine Fager Sundquist) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Fairbanks, Morse & Co., Seattle, Farm Engines (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Federal Land Bank, Spokane and Farm Credit Assoc., Yakima (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco, Appointment as a Director of Seattle Branch (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Rev. K. Forsman and Reuben Forsman, Cadillac, Michigan (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - A. B. Fosseen & Co., Inc., Yakima, account statements (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Fruit Purchase Contracts, Statements (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence G, Misc. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Growers Service Company, Yakima, account statements (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Guaranty Trust Company, Yakima (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Gwin, White & Prince, Inc., Seattle, apple brokers (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Corresponcence H, Misc. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - H & B Motor Car Co., Inc, Yakima, Moline Tractor dealer, account dispute, 1919-20 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Florence Harrison, Dean of the College of Home Economics, WSC, apple v. orange controversy, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - F. D. Heald, Plant Pathologist, WSC (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Harold Hoegland, Dean, Yakima Junior College (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - E. O. Holland, President, WSC (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence I, Misc. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence J, Misc. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - C. Maurice Johnson, Oil Accountant, Wichita Falls, Texas (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Edward C. Johnson, Dean of the College of Agriculture, WSC (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Mrs. J. P. Johnson, Galesburg, Illinois (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence K, Misc. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - C. M. Kopp, Yakima, carlot shippers, account statements (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence L, Misc. (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - W. J. Lane Co., Farm Lands, Loans, Ins., Fargo, N. Dak. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Larson and Sundquist, growers (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Libby, McNeill & Libby, fruit buyer, statements and receipts (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Lindeman Power Equipment Co., Yakima, account statements (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence M, Misc. (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Magnolia Fertilizer Co., Seattle (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Martin General Agency and Yakima Investment Co. (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Catherine May, M.C. (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - T. A. Merrill, WSC (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - O. M. Morris, Professor of Horticulture, WSC (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - D. V. Morthland, Esq., regarding Sunnyslope Development Co. (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence N, Misc. (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Naches Cold Storage Co., Gleed, statements and receipts (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Naches Heights Nursery, Yakima, statements and receipts (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - National Recovery Administration (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Nile Creek Lumber Co., Naches, invoices (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence O, Misc. (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - A. L. Ostrander Fruit Co., receipts (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence P, Misc. (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Pacific Power and Light (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Pacific Power and Light, statements (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Walt Paeschke, Mabton (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Perham Fruit Co., Yakima (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Perham Fruit Co., Yakima, statements and contracts (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Personnel Security Board, U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, Hanford office (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Phoenix Mutual Life Insurance Co., Wiliam Laney (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Jack Preissner, Yakima (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Prentice Packing & Storage, Yakima, statements and receipts (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence R, Misc. (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Richey & Gilbert Co., Yakima Valley Fruits, Yakima (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Richey & Gilbert Co., statements and contracts (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Rumsey Pump Co., Seneca Falls, New York (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence S, Misc. (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - C. S. Schaefer Company, Yakima (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Mrs. Arthur Segerquist (Louise Johnson), Valdez, Alaska (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Sellers & Stone, Yakima Valley Fruits, Yakima (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Sellers & Stone, statements and receipts (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Sizer & Co., Veneer Products, Tacoma (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - H. R. Spinner, Wholesaler, Yakima (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Anthony Spuler, Entomologist, WSC (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Stark Bro's Nurseries & Orchard Co., Louisiana, Mo. (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Stubbs Fruit & Storage Co., Packers and Shippers, Yakima (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Stubbs Fruit & Storage Co., statements and receipts (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Hjalmar Sundquist (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Ralph Sundquist Family (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Sundquist v. McNeff (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Correspondence T, Misc. (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Taxes, Income, Federal Returns, 1921-32 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Taxes, State, County, Local, 1920-1939 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Correspondence U, Misc. (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Correspondence V, Misc. (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Correspondence W, Misc. (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Arthur Wallander, Chicago (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Warren & Co., Bulk Fruit, Yakima (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Washington Fruit & Produce Co., statements and receipts (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Washington Growers' Clearinghouse Association (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - First Bank of White Bluffs, White Bluffs, Wash. (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Winthrop Orchards, Inc., Gleed (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Correspondence Y, Misc. (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Yakima Fruit & Cold Storage Co., Yakima (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Yakima Fruit Growers Association, part 1 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Yakima Fruit Growers Association, part 2 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Yakima Fruit Growers Association, C. D. Tracy (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Yakima Horticultural Club (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Yakima Mortgage Loan Co. and Yakima Mortgage & Bond Co. (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Yakima Title Guaranty & Abstract Co., filings (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Yakima Trust Company, Yakima First National Bank (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Yakima Valley Growers' Spray Residue Committee (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Yakima Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) (Box 5, Folder 119)
- Series 2. Subject Files
  - American Institute of Agriculture, marketing pamphlets (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - An Analysis of Orchard Operations as Related to... Employment and Relief Problems... Chelan County (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Miss S. I. Anthon, Yakima teacher (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Apple Grading, questionnaires, news articles, etc., 1930-1939 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Apple Packing, Cull Account, figures, etc., 1930-1939 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Apple Production Statistics, Sundquist Orchards, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Apple Production Statistics, 1920-27 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - Apple Production, Study of a Pool, 1925-26 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Apple reports: Apple Facts (1935); Newtown Study (1953); Producer-Consumer Surplus Apple Campaign (1948), 1935-1953 (Box 6, Folder 126.1)
  - An Appreciation of E. A. Bryan, by R. C. McCroskey (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - Automobile Registrations, Sundquist, 1920-1939 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - The Cause and Prevention of Storage Rots, W. A. Luce, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - A History of the Yakima-Tieton Irrigation Project, by Guy C. Finley, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Bartlett Pear Commodity Comm., Pear Selling Prices, 1933-34 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Pear Growers League Annual, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Codling Moth Traps, by Anthony Spuler, Wash. Ag. Expt. Stn. (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Cold Storage Building Fires, Yakima. news articles, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Wilson Compton, press releases (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Wilson Compton, Resignation as WSC President, news articles (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Wilson Compton, Westminster Foundation, WSC, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Current Transportation Problem of the Far West Apple Industry, by Chas. B. Bowling, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Federal Reserve Bank (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - Fruit Consumption Statistics, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - Fruit Grading Standards, State of Washington and Northwest Canners Association, 1919-32 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - The Gamma Theta Chapter of Beta Theta Pi, WSC, newsletter (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - B. F. Goodrich Travelog, auto trip, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - History of Delicious Apple Variety, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - Alexander Hamilton Institute Correspondence Course Assignments, 1923-25 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - License for Handlers of Fresh Deciduous Tree Fruit Grown in... WA, OR, MT, ID, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Luncheon Group, Chinook Hotel, photograph, Dec. 1975 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Meet Ralph Sundquist, Walston Round-up, Mar-65 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Naches-Selah Irrigation District, By-Laws, Bond Issue, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - Newspaper Articles, miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - Northwest Fruit Industries, Inc, 1930-1939 (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Northwest Perishable Traffic Bureau, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - Orchard Management Advertisement on Alar, for Uniroyal, Photo of Marvin Sundquist (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - The Outlook for Future Control of Codling Moth in Wenatchee-Okanogan District, 1930-19369 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - Pacific Coast Packer, 8-Aug-36 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Photographs, Post Cards, miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - Procedure and Information for Personnel Security Review Boards, Book No. 2, Hanford Operations Office, and other material, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - Real Estate Contract with Guaranty Trust Co., Yakima (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - Recital Programs (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - Rotary Club, Yakima chapter (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - The Royal Order of Hairy Chested Men, Ralph Sundquist membership certificate, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Roza Canal (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - Silver Beaver Award, Boy Scouts of America, 2/18/1963 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Some Believe-It-or-Not's of the Apple Industry, by Clyde D. Merchant, 1935-1939 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Some Facts Connected with the Spray Residue Situation, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Some Marketing Problems, by E. A Smith, 1930-1939 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Frank Stubbs... Yakima Pioneer and Community Leader, Yakima Valley Sun, Gary L. Jackson, 9/18/1975 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Sundquist Apples, box label (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - Sundquist Fruit & Cold Storage, From Tree to Trade, advertisement on letterhead (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - Sundquist Fruit & Cold Storage, advertisement, The Packer, 10/16/1976 (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Elaine Fager Sundquist, biographical material (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - Ralph Sundquist, newspaper articles on or by him (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - Ralph Sundquist... Active Community Leader... Yakima Valley Sun, Grace Millay, 11/13/1975 (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - To My Christmas Carol, by Hjalmar Sundquist, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - S.S. Virginia, menus from maiden voyage, Dec. 1928-Jan. 1929 (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - William Hunter Volk, patent application for fungicide, insecticide, oil, 1924-26, and 1933 letter, 1924-1926 (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - Washington Nursery Co, trees sales brochure (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - Washington State Horticultural Assn, annual meeting programs (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - M.V. Yakima, Puget Sound Ferry, christening, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - Yakima Horticultural Club, attendence and dues, 1920-1929 (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Yakima Valley Fruit Trafic Assn, Statistical Book Revisions, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 180)
  - Yakima Valley Society for Spastics and Other Handicapped Persons, minute book, 1946-1957 (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - Yakima Valley Traffic and Credit Association, Bulletin 79, Apple Grading Rules, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Yakima YMCA, brochures (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - Yakima YMCA, new building construction, dedication, 1950-1959 (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Yakima YMCA, newspaper feature articles (Box 8, Folder 185)
- Series 3. Reports by Ralph Sundquist
  - Agriculture in the Yakima Valley: Past, Present, and Future, 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - An Analysis of Successes and Failures in Codling Moth Control in 1938 (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - The Apple Boom, Pollenization, Fertilization, outline, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 188)
  - Botanical Ink Drawings, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 189)
  - Culture Media, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 190)
  - Cultures, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 191)
  - Economical Control of the Codling Moth in 1932 (Box 9, Folder 192)
  - Farm Management Demonstrations in Yakima County, Washington, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 193)
  - A Farm Management Survey in the Selah Valley, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 194)
  - History of the State College (Box 9, Folder 195)
  - Interest in the Apple Industry, 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 196)
  - Manuscript on Spraying Orchards, 1930-1939 (Box 9, Folder 197)
  - Means of Accomplishing Orchard Tillage, 1920-1929 (Box 9, Folder 198)
  - Observations of the Apple Industry of California (Box 9, Folder 199)
  - Observations on the Pear Industry of California (Box 9, Folder 200)
  - Observations on Cold Weather Damage to Apples, Nov. 1935 (Box 9, Folder 201)
  - Orchard Survey form, 1915-1919 (Box 9, Folder 202)
  - Order of Work for Botany 56. Laboratory Work (Box 9, Folder 203)
  - Origins of the Northwest Apple Box... (Box 9, Folder 204)
  - Our Losing Battle Against Powdery Mildew of the Apple (Box 9, Folder 205)
  - Principles Underlying Pruning Practice, 7-Mar-34 (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - A Re-Arranged Farmstead, 1920-1929 (Box 9, Folder 207)
  - Reminiscences of Yakima College Founding, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 208)
  - Report, Codling Moth Control Experiments of Associated Oil Company, 1927-1928 (Box 9, Folder 209)
  - Report on Codling Moth Experiments using Pretrotine Products, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - Should We have Federal Aid to Education, 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - Statement of Ralph Sundquist: Marketing Agreement Hearing, May 13, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 212)
  - Theoretical Farm Report, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 213)
  - Twenty Years Experience With Ammonium Sulphate, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 214)
  - Why Are Washington Apples so Frequently Not Delivered to the Consumer in Satisfactory Condition?, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 215)
  - What Determines Apple Prices, 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 216)
  - What it Means to Practice Christian Principles in Everyday Business, Ralph Sundquist (Box 9, Folder 217)
  - When We Hear the Dollar's Whisper (Box 9, Folder 218)
- Series 4. Civic Interests
  - 4.1 Lower Naches Telephone Company
    - Articles of Incorporation (Box 10, Folder 219)
    - Correspondence, 1908-1955 (Box 10, Folder 220)
    - Historical Sketches (Box 10, Folder 221)
    - Legal Documents (Box 10, Folder 222)
    - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - News Articles (Box 10, Folder 224)
    - Proposed Farmer Line Rate Increases by Pacific Telephone and Telegraph Company (Box 10, Folder 225)
    - President's Report, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 226)
    - Rural Telephone Loan Program, REA (Box 10, Folder 227)
    - Stockholders' Meetings, Reports, 1948-50 (Box 10, Folder 228)
  - 4.2 First Presbyterian Church of Yakima
    - Articles of Incorporation (1885) and Historical Chronology acquired from Wayne Walker, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 229)
    - Budgets, 1960-1969 (Box 10, Folder 230)
    - Building Remodeling, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 231)
    - Camp Ghormley, 1937-42 (Box 10, Folder 232)
    - Dedication for Addition to the Organ, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 233)
    - Dedicatory Address, Piper Organ, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 234)
    - J. Dupre, Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 235)
    - History of First Presbyterian Church of North Yakima (Box 10, Folder 236)
    - Information Regarding Boy Scouts of America, Troop # 1, First Presbyterian Chuch, Yakima.. (Box 10, Folder 237)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 238)
    - New First Presbyterian Church, Dedicatory Pamphlet, 1920-1929 (Box 10, Folder 239)
    - The New First Presbyterian Church Edifice, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 240)
    - Photographs of Organists
      - David Craighead (Box 10, Folder 241)
      - Marcel Dupre (Box 10, Folder 242)
      - Flor Peeters (Box 10, Folder 243)
      - Alexander Schreiner (Box 10, Folder 244)
    - Pipe Organ Concert Programs (Box 10, Folder 245)
    - Recollections by Reuben G. Benz, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - Alexander Schreiner, Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 247)
    - Tower Talk, Welcome Howard Childers, 22-Nov-74 (Box 10, Folder 248)
    - Voice of the Organ, KIT radio 1280 AM, Yakima, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 249)
    - Ward Chapel (Box 10, Folder 250)